Without meditation you don't understand what is best for you.
So today is a day when you have to promise me that you will meditate every night, every
evening, maybe in the morning hours.
Whenever it is possible, if you can go into meditative mood, you are in contact with
this divine power.
Then whatever is good for you, whatever good for your society, for your country, all
is done by this divine power.
You don't have to overpower the divine power.
You don't have to order, you don't have to ask.
Just if you meditate, you are one with this all-pervading power which is another great blessings
to us.
Unless and until your Sastra is open, all the blessings of the divine power cannot come
to you, cannot.
Maybe you might get some money, you might get some jobs, you might get this and that.
But your own development is only possible when you meditate and your Sastra is completely
open and open to truth.
Now the truth is that this divine power is a passion, is love.
This is the truth.
They say, God is love, God is truth.
So the equation has to be made, that truth is love and love is truth.
But it's not a truth that as you have for your own children, you have for your family,
attached, attached love is not truth.
If you are attached to somebody, then you never see the bad points of that person.
If you are angry with somebody, then you can never see the good points of that person.
But it's a complete, detached love and that love is extremely powerful because whenever
you project that love to anyone, you'll be surprised.
The problems of that person will be solved, his personality will improve, everything
will work out in a very big way and his life will be changed.
But if you are attached to anything whatsoever, that attachment itself causes problems and
doesn't allow such to grow.
This attachment could be any kind.
For example, you can be attached to your country, it took, attached to your society, attached
to your family.
It can be of any kind.
But when Sastra Raya is open, you learn one thing is detachment.
It just happens that you get detached.
Though I mean you are not running away.
As it is in Sahaja Yoga, we don't believe in people who run away from society and go
to Himalaya's or that I call them as escapicism.
That is not the point.
What happens is that you are there.
You see everyone, you watch everyone.
You know everyone, you are close to everyone.
But you are attached person.
It's a state of mind that you achieve when Sastra Raya is open.
Then that state you are dealing with people, you are dealing with problems, you are dealing
with situations, but you are not involved in it.
It's no involvement and that involvement which you had before can never give a complete
insight.
What is happening, what is the truth is about any situation.
So this detachment helps the greatest thing of the detachment is that you are not affected.
No use saying that, oh you are not affected, mother, so how can you feel for another person,
how can you have compassion for another person?
Because if you feel for another person, then only you can solve the problem.
But this feeling that you have is again a kind of an attachment.
It is not a real feeling because it does help.
The person is crying, you are also crying.
The person is troubled, you are also in trouble.
And this does not help that person, nor will it help you.
So to have detached in no way means you do not feel the another person.
You do feel, you feel the agony of that person, the trouble of that person, of the whole society
sometimes and of the whole country.
But that your feeling is so detached that the all-pervading power takes over.
First we must have full faith in the capability of this all-pervading power.
As soon as we are detached, you say you do it.
Finished.
Once you say that you are going to do it, it's you who is going to do it.
Whole thing changes completely because you transfer all your responsibilities, all your
problems to this Divine Power which is so powerful, which is so capable, which can work
out anything.
So whenever you think that this problem, you are going to solve, you are the one who is
going to do it.
Then all right, the Divine Power says, all right, try your luck.
But if you can really put this problem to the Divine Power, it will work out.