The mind about which we speak and depend upon is a myth.
There's nothing like mind.
Brain is reality, not the mind.
Mind is created by us reacting to outside.
Either we react to conditioning or to our ego.
Does this mind is created like bubbles on the ocean of reality?
But that's not reality.
With this mind, whatever we decide, we know is very limited, elusive and sometimes shocking.
The mind always moves in a linear direction.
And because there's no reality in it, it recoils and boom rags.
Does all the enterprises, all the projections so far we have gone, it seems come back to us.
Whatever they discover comes back to us as a big destructive power or a very big shock.
So one has to decide what to do, how to be out of this trap of our mind.
Kundalini is the solution when she's awake, she takes you, that awakely, she takes you beyond
your mind.
The first thing is to go beyond your mind.
With mind you will do many things, but it will not be satisfying, it will be not a solution,
it will not hurt her.
And when we start depending too much on our mind, we develop all kinds of physical
and emotional problems.
Now the latest is the stress.
Stress and the stress has no solution they say.
But in Sahaja Yoga we find the solution.
By crossing over this mind, it's like a barrier for our advancement.
So when you get your realization you must understand that your Kundalini has taken your
attention beyond the mind.
Now this reaction to outside has come because we human beings have a rhythm like, or we
can say, prism like, skull.
And when the energy passes into it, I'll explain it in my books.
It goes into bifurcations or you can say, reflections by which our attention goes out and we react.
If we react too much, then these bubbles create a very horrible mind which can lead to any
kind of thing.
It justifies itself its temposir ego.
The ego and the conditioning that creates this mind starts using and this mind for the
purpose of their fulfillment of their, all the accumulation of ideas and thoughts which
has no backing, which has no reality to it.
Just like we make the computer, ultimately we become slaves of the computer, we make
the watches ourselves and then we become slaves of the watches.
That's how it dominates human beings.
And when a person who has a very strong mind decides to destroy like Hitler did with
some idea, he can't go on destroying which has a very far-fished effect on our culture,
on our spirituality.
Now the first step is to become thoughtlessly aware where you cross your mind, you go
above your mind.
Mind cannot affect.
This is the first stage as we call it, thoughtless awareness.
Second one is where you see, start seeing the working of this paravasaitanya, of this
all-pervading power and you start becoming aware that there is lot of truth in what
Mahpatici says, that there is this power which works out many things.
It works miraculously so many things for you.
It gives you blessing, it guides you, it helps you in so many ways it helps.
It gives you good health, good wealth and also a very good society of very beautiful people
in the collect.
All that you can see clearly is happening here.
There are a lot of questions.
Now this happening of achieving thoughtless awareness is very simple and easy but to
maintain at that point is difficult.
Anything you see you react to get to that point in thoughtless awareness is first to change
your attention.
Now for example, once we were climbing a very high mountain to see one temple called
palitana, myself, my son-in-law and my daughter.
I was really tired because we had to climb I don't know how many steps.
And when we went up we were tired and there was a little canopy made of beautiful marble
carving so we just lay down there.
They were very tired and they said, what is this kind of a temple, a dressing?
While I looked up and I saw lots of beautiful elephants were caught.
So I told my son-in-law, look at these elephants.
They all have takes of different types.
He said, mummy, they are all dying, how can you see the tails of elephants?
What is just to divert their attention from that darkness, I told them that why not see
these tails of the elephant which is very different?
So what happens that when you are putting your attention so much to outside all the time,
then you must first of all also divert your attention.
For example, you see these beautifully made things here.
Your attention is something else just try to enjoy the beauty of that.
They are a beautiful carpets, just look at them without thinking because they don't belong
to you so no headache, they belong to somebody else.
It's very good.
Otherwise if it belongs to you, you start thinking, oh my God, I spread in the mirror, what
will happen there to be scared or something like that.
That's common human reaction.
But if it doesn't belong to you, you can watch it nicely.
Now you watch it and don't think.
You'll be amazed when you see the beauty that is put inside this.
You'll see the artist who has put his joy is exuberance in it.
And it will be amazed after realization that this exuberance will fill into you and a cool
kind of relaxation will come into you.
And this Kundalini will rise and it will become steady in your thoughtlessness.
So whenever you look at anything, look at any beautiful thing, even say to the exuberance,
just watch the man who is the exuberant.
Watching him itself gives him blessings, gives him better ideas.
You get also ideas which are coming from reality, which are there.
How to make this man a successful person or this country a successful democracy?
All these things happen when your attention is diverted from criticizing, from reacting
just you watch, become the witness, try to be the witness of it.
It's not so very yet practiced so far as we, that whenever even we get our continued
realization, we don't realize that we have to be dissatisfied.
When you start to test it through your spirit, then you don't see the bad points of another,
that you see the good points.
You just pick up the person with very good points.
I see, so once you see that with this state in love this and you start enjoying another
person, you start enjoying everything that is there.
And a small blade of grass, you can enjoy.