I bow to all the seekers of truth.
First of all, we have to know what is the truth.
People are seeking, seeking, seeking, all over, but they don't know what they are seeking
and what should they get after their seeking.
This seeking can lead you into many diverse directions.
Some of them could be very, very dangerous and absolutely misleading.
And many must have all of us so felt that.
I'm sure there are many who have found it out, but they think there is no way they can
return.
The seeking is very simple to understand that you want to know yourself.
All the time you say, I want this, I like this, I, this, I like that.
But who is this, I?
What is it?
Who is this one myself?
What am I?
Do I know anything about myself?
That's very superficial knowledge we have about ourselves.
Everybody has said, all the religions have said, you should know yourself.
There's no difference on this point.
Actually in all religions, if you go in the essence, there's no difference.
According to time, it was little bit stressed on one point and sometimes on another point.
But the fundamental thing is that you have to know yourself.
How do you know yourself is the point.
You will say, do this, give up everything, give up your family, give up everything,
wear this kind of dress, cut your hair or shave your head and all that nonsense.
It's so outward.
If you put little bit of your intelligence, you'll see, it's all outward.
It's so skin deep, it has no meaning.
So what has to happen?
We talk of a last breakthrough of the evolution.
How do we achieve it?
When you are evolved up to the state of human beings, we have to know one thing for definite
that there's something missing within us.
Otherwise world would have been a most beautiful place, the paradise, to live it.
But something wrong with the human beings and what is that is to understand how we have
come through evolution.
And as human beings, there are so many things of the animal stage lingering within us.
The way we talk, the way we try to upris others, the way we talk to sort of dominate others,
one way we want to snatch everything, the way we are only worried about our food, this,
that all this is not really a noble human beings science.
These are all lingering from that animal instinct.
All right, we have to accept because we are human beings, so they are to be there.
I think so much frightening.
But also we have one more thing that we think and we think and think and think and think
and think of ourselves.
Sometimes we think we should protest for this.
Sometimes we feel that we must become very violent.
All these things are coming from our human mind.
Sometimes we won't be violent for something, just for violence sake.
They'll be violent, all right.
But for their own purpose of killing some animal or something.
But here we have groups and groups of people who just enjoy violence.
This is another development in the human awareness, I think, that we enjoy destruction of others.
But also there is a seeking.
This is the sign that people want their evolution.
They want to evolve into a better personality, that they want to become something which is
complete.
Now how do you achieve it?
Now I must say that we have not achieved our evolution ourselves up to the human level.
So to achieve a higher awareness there must be some arrangement with you next.
And that is the arrangement we are not aware of.
And that arrangement is that within you is the power, it's your own power to give you
this last breakthrough through the awakening of that power.
Already you have been told about it.
It exists, it's there, and it is the right of every human being to get his self-knowledge
self-realization.
Surger, some is born with you.
With you is born the right.
And why should we not ask under fundamental rights, society, that we should have our self-realization?
Which is your own?
It is there already placed within you.
You don't have to do anything.
Of course you can't pay for it.
How much did you pay for your evolution so far?
And how can it be different from different people?
Because in every human being this power which we call as Kundalini exists, whether he
is white, black, yellow, blue, any color, whether it belongs to North or South.
Whether he belongs to this country or that country, they all have this power universally placed
in their Kundalini.
Even if I say everybody has a heart, so why should we have differentiation?
But this mind, this human mind creates this differentiation and this problem saying that
of course they are not of our country, they don't belong to a group.
And like animals again we start for getting into groups, groups of different, I don't know,
denomination.
Like some people have their folk and spoon put this way.
So they are one group.
Some people drink coffee so they have a group like that, is it?
We are very good at farming groups.
This is also animal instinct I think that we try to form groups of such stupid things.
And then we can have wars because we must fight.
We are a group, something great, so we should fight others.
All these instincts that are within us are inheritance.
They have come to us, they say it is in our genes.
Can we change the genes?
Can we transform our personality into something higher?
And for that I tell you there is a power within us.
All of you have that power within you.
And what does it give you?
It own passes through six centers, has told to you, it nourishes it, it integrates it
and ultimately it pierces through the last four-dened bone area.
We can call that actualization of the baptism and is connected to the all-pervading power
of divine love.
Again I say love, divine compassion and divine love.
So you get connected to that power which is all-pervading.
If you ask a doctor who runs our heart, he'll say, is the autonomous nervous system?
Who is the auto?
Who does all these things?
Who does all the living works?
Look at this flower, it's beautiful.
Who has made these flowers, it's different, different flower?
How does this mother differentiates and how she gives all these flowers?
Do we think about it?
We take it for granted.
All living work we take it for granted, but it is done by this divine power.
Believe me, there is this divine power around us which protects us, which looks after us,
which guides us.
And also above all it loves us and it cares for us.
It wants that we should all receive the blessings of this all-pervading power.