But with this power you become so much full of compassion.
Then your attention goes from you to others, what you can do for others, how can you give
them realization?
And suddenly you discover that around you is so many destructive forces, so many disturbing
forces, so many problems, suddenly you find a discipline.
If you can transform human being, but it's no question of transformation, I would say it
is the question of evolutionary process.
And when this takes place you find you are transformed completely and thousands have to
be transformed, thousands and thousands and millions and millions.
But somehow America has a different type of approach to spirituality.
They think if I don't take money then something wrong with me.
I must accept money, they have told me so many things, some experts came and told me,
explained to me all the economics and all that which I don't understand.
And they think that it should be sellable.
Can't understand this kind of a thing.
How much will you pay for Christ?
How much will you pay for any saintly personality?
Because it is, this value cannot be, it's invaluable.
Something that the most invaluable for you is to know yourself.
If you have not known yourself, you are still going round and round and round in the
mad rush of thinking.
Even Einstein will be surprised, has talked about it, that he was trying to find the theory
of relativity.
I just can't find it.
So he went into his garden and was playing with them, so bubbles and suddenly from somewhere
unknown, that's what he said.
The theory of relativity dawned upon him.
And he called that unknown area, he called them by a name, you see.
And that name is rather to me, not so precise.
But he says there is an area which you can exploit, by which you can understand for the
future generation, for the future scientist, where you get the ideas from there.
And he said for that you must have a kind of a personality that can perceive that torsion
area from where the ideas are coming.
If he can enter into that area, you can get the full idea as to what is reality.
He calls it cognitive, he says he is a cognitive science.
And such a person can tell you so many things which, when you put it to the scientific test
you'll find is absolutely correct.
And this is what happened to him because himself was a realized soul.
And many people like Newton himself was a realized soul.
Abraham Lincoln was a realized soul.
But they could not tell about it to others because nobody would believe and anybody tried
to tell anything they just used to torture them.
Every saint has real say in Tamil, has been tortured, every sushi has been tortured.
In our country especially many saints have been very badly treated.
Also in other countries, why?
Because they are only one and maybe people were jealous that how could they know so much,
how could they talk about so many things.
Now with all this, now only thing if I have done anything is very simple that I thought
no use giving this realization to one or two persons which was the tradition to give to
only one to one.
But now I felt it won't work out.
We have to have it for the masses.
And I just what I did was to find out a method by which I can give our mass realization.
That's all.
Which is a simple thing.
And that is working and it's work very well.
As I said in America they just think of this another achievement of human beings that
they know about money.
So money, money, money, everything money.
So they can't understand even spirituality without money.
But in a place like, say we can say Russia.
Russia people, Russian people had no freedom as you have.
And they had oppression from all sides in there.
As you know the whole thing was a, was a communist country.
And in that communism they were completely oppressed.
So as a result they went inside, gave us.
And tried to find out solutions inside.
So when they saw me just seeing me, I don't know how thousands of them came.
Now we are thousands and thousands and thousands of people in Russia alone.
So in other some countries.
I mean, I mean I see here, I'm just thinking in Russia we have to take.
We cannot put it in a hall where we have to have a big tent or Olympics where they had
some sort of a thing like that.
So the trouble is we should give up this idea that I can find it for myself.
This is very, very common.
You cannot.
This is the only evolution in which you have to get it from an enlightened person.
You have to humble on this point.
But I can't get it on my own.
I can find my own way.
You cannot.
You'll be lost.
You have to have somebody who is already enlightened.
Now how to get an enlightened person also?
How to know?
Because after realization you know the absolute truth.
On your fingertips you can feel the centers of other person.
If something is fishy you can feel it.
If somebody is cheating you can feel it.
Everything.
Your fingers speak.
This is what Momasabha said at the time of resurrection your hands will speak.
Clearly.
How can hands speak?
This is how?
And all these five fingers are the centers, sixth and seventh centers.