So, it is important to understand the first rule of Sahaja Yoga is that you look at yourself.
How are you?
Are you really progressing or you are worried about other things like your business, these
are you worried about your recent or are you worried about your recent or are you doing
about it? That has to be the main object of life. The rest of the things follow it.
Once you ascend the whole cosmos can look after your problems, but you must ascend into
the kingdom of God. That's the main point is. So, first of all, you have to ascertain about
yourself. Am I ascending? Am I transforming? Am I giving up all my bad habits?
Am I getting rid of my temper? Am I getting peaceful? Am I now sweet? Or am I now still the same?
Horrible, criticizer of others. Just put your attention to yourself and see for yourself.
It's like a mirror. You start seeing yourself in the mirror. What's wrong with you?
And then you try to correct it. Now, second point is that you must see your vibrations.
What centers you are catching? For that you have to give yourself a bundle.
You give yourself a bundle and see for yourself what's wrong with you. When you give
yourself a bundle you will know about your chakras.
Now, then you have to go further. See, you find yourself that your right side is hot.
What you do is to put your right side towards the photograph and left side up towards the ether.
The ether takes away the heat. But what actually happens is that your right side gets
the vibration and the heat is pushed towards your left and passes out into the ether.
Now, this heat comes from too much futuristic living.
Most people who are too much futuristic, they have too much heat.
And too much heat has to go away. And when this heat starts going away and you are amazed
how it works. For that there are various things we have to use.
But mainly for right-sided people they should not use any light at all.
They should not sit in the sun. They should sit in the moonlight.
They should read some poetry. They should not tie up watches.
They should not look at time. They should allow the time to pass.
And they should just become very emotional people. They should sing songs of bhakti.
They should not do hatioga. There are so many things they should not do if they are right-sided.
You will be surprised how people have been helped through this kind of a treatment which treats one side of your being.
The left hand side people are the people as you know are the ones who are dosai,
who bear up lots of things from others and cry and weep and all that time are on the loser's end.
Such people have problems also because all their organs are liturgy and they have problems of a liturgy.
Heart, liturgy, liver, liturgy, intestines, everything becomes very liturgy.
You get pains in the body. Right-sided person doesn't get any pain.
himself he gives pain to others. He is very sarcastic, he is very aggressive.
He troubles others. But the left-sided people have pains themselves.
They get pain here and a pain there and a pain here.
So the left side is to be cleared as you know very well through the light.
Light is put before the photograph, left hand was the photograph, right hand on the mother earth.
So the left hand gets the light and the light passes through and the negative energy of the left side passes through the right hand and the right hand is on the mother earth.
The mother earth is the one who sucks in all these negative forces of the left hand side.
So these are the two sides which we clear. But once you have cleared these two sides then you can use the photograph.
Sit with your both the hands or the photograph and put both the feet in the water a little bit of salt in it.
And what five, ten minutes you must allow vibrations to clear you out.
Then wipe your feet, put the water properly into some disposal and then sit down for meditation.
If you can do that every day, even ten minutes is more than sufficient.
Don't have to do anything in an extreme manner.
In the morning time you have to give yourself a banda when you are going out.
Don't go out without giving a banda.
And attention should be all the time inside in the sense that walking on the road people have a habit of seeing this,
seeing that, seeing like that, the attention gets littered away.
What you should do is to see about three feet or four feet at the most on the ground and not above.
Because you can see all the beautiful children, flowers, everything.
There's nothing very beautiful about that.
So better is to see only up three, four feet if possible to fix your attention.
So the attention becomes concentrated and you feel very relaxed and relieved
of too much of wobbling of your eyes.
Eyes are very important.
Very important and as you will notice because you are all realize so that your eyes now have got a glint,
a kind of a light in the eye.
And that light shows that you are a real resource.