In the West we have become very speed, not up.
I have to bring down the speed.
We have to use meditative process that we feel our peace within ourselves.
So the thoughts are bombarding our minds and we react very fast to others and to these
thoughts.
So one has to be aware, one has to be knowing what is happening within yourself, that the
thoughts are bombarding you, you are trying to ascend and you find it very difficult
to get rid of the thoughts.
The thought process can start by your conditioning or by your ego, only two problems.
And you are the one who is under the challenge.
So you have got these simple people in the village who start watching everything but
they do not react.
If you do not react then your thoughts will give up.
So the first thing should be to watch yourself that you are not reacting.
But you are experiencing and enjoying the silence, the subtleties, the beauty, the glory.
If you are being as well as whatever is around, you don't have to force yourself to
break this habit, but just to be on the watch out.
It's not necessary to talk too much about it also, nor it is necessary to think about
anything.
And supposing you see a tree, so it's a tree only, what are we going to think about it?
And whatever we may think about it is going to be the tree.
So there's no harm in appearing little bit stupid, doesn't matter.
But this is the basic thing is that when we start analyzing, we are breaking our own
nerves and poisoning our own mind and brain.
So to watch something without analysis, without thinking about it is reality.
If you can achieve that point where you watch everything without reacting, you are in reality.
And then only the penetration into the subtleties of your surroundings, of your relationships,
your friendships, the whole universe, dance upon it.
So to judge others, to think of others, what they are doing, what's wrong with them, about
anything whatsoever you may think is wrong.
It's not going to be corrected.
Like I know some people who are specially bureaucrats, they are traveling, supposing by the car.
Then they will say, I think you see this road should have gone this way.
Or I think it would have been nice if this house was facing the other way.
But it's not, you see, it is not going to face.
It is going to be the way it is.
So what is the use of wasting your brain, your mind, your thought in suggesting something
which doesn't work out?
Never going to work out either.
So when we start like I think these trees should have been little taller, but they are
not.
I think that the crows should stop their noise, they will not.
So just accept it.
Acceptance is the way we are going to enjoy.
Acceptance doesn't mean tolerance because tolerance means you have to work very hard to
accept that the trees are of the same height.
They can't grow.
It's too much for you.
When you say I have to tolerate it, you see because my mind doesn't accept.
So acceptance as it is whatever you see, acceptance.
And that is how people grow I have seen, those who start accepting.
That's the sign.
That's the sign of their strength and their depth, like the propensity of this Mother Earth.
She is what she is and she bears whatever is there.
If you put a heavy thing on her, she'll put equal and opposite force and bear it.
She doesn't say I am tolerating it, I am exerting any pressure, but she's just accepting.
So the witnessing and awareness develops when we start just accepting things as they are.
I think it doesn't work out.
I think it would have been better like this just work out.