So one must know that there must be something more we have to go.
I would put it this way that in the West whatever knowledge we have had about science or
about other things is like the knowledge of the tree which is outside.
Now whatever Dr. Warren has told you is the knowledge of the roots.
Now supposing if the East has learnt this knowledge from you has tried to understand
this knowledge of science of course which is not very fruitful also but doesn't matter.
They have tried to learn this knowledge of science.
Why not we try to learn the knowledge of the roots?
The roots of the tree of life.
Why should we not try to find out what are the roots which are to be nourished, which
were neglected and that's why we have problems.
These are the roots within us which are being described.
And when these roots are understood then only we will see that something more has to
happen that we have to feel those roots we don't feel them on our central nervous system.
We have no sensitivity at all within us.
For example now supposing a person is getting mad he is not conscious of it that he is
getting mad or if he develops some disease he doesn't become conscious of it till he
gets some pain.
But actually these centers are the subtle energy centers which give energy to the plexuses
and look after us very well.
But how to enlighten these centers?
That was the big problem.
How to enlighten these centers so that we start feeling our roots?
For that God Almighty who is our father who is very kind and gentle in his all care has
made this beautiful thing within us and all of them are like the milestones of our evolution.
These centers are to be enlightened and when they are to be enlightened something has
to be done.
For that in the triangular bone here is placed the energy called the Kundalini.
It's a Sanskrit word meaning the coils.
It is in three and a half coils for a particular mathematical reason.
A mathematician can understand three and a half is very important coefficient.
Three and a half coils it is placed there and this has to be awakened like a primule in
a seed to enlighten all these six centers and ultimately enter through this center which
is the sixth one in this order.
If the seventh one lives down below the Kundalini this is the important thing that has to happen
to us to become the spirit that Christ has told us that we have to become the spirit, that
we are to be born again.
It is again certifying ourselves that we are born again you do not become.
Let us accept one thing we are not going to live with myths and dishonesty.
If we are going to be honest with ourselves it is beneficial to us.
It is benevolent for us to be honest with ourselves and to realize that by giving ourselves
certificates we do not become anything.
It's only a mental projection.
Whether I call myself a Christian or a Muslim or a Hindu makes no difference whatsoever,
whatever dress I wear or howsoever I comb my hair makes no difference to me at all.
In all honesty we have to perceive and see to reach that absolute stage this Kundalini
has to rise.
There is no other way out and this is what is the Holy Ghost within us.
This is the Holy Ghost.
Is the reflection of the Holy Ghost and Holy Ghost is the energy of God which is love,
which is His desire.
His desire is the Holy Ghost and is reflected within us as the Kundalini.
So the desire of God is that you should become the citizen of His Kingdom.
That you should enter into His Kingdom and enjoy all the fruits of His blessings, understandably,
knowingly on your central nervous system.
This is His pure desire and if that pure desire within us rises then we see that all other
desires were useless and they are not pure-righted because we have some desire say for example we
want to have a car or a car or they want to have a house or a house.
We never satisfied.
In general it is said that bonds are not satiated because they are not bonds, they are artificial
bonds, the real bond, the real desire is this one.
This energy of pure desire that says you have to unite, unite with the divine with the
all-pervading power of God.
That is our pure desire and unless and until that desire is completed you may do any kind
of things, you may go to all kinds of things, try anything you can never achieve.
Now this is a living process because God is a living being, He is not empty words, He
is not just something like a dead book, He is not.
He is a living God, He is a living energy and this is a living process.
So it has to be spontaneous.
It has to be spontaneous if it is living.
For example there is a seed and you want to sprout it, can you order it?
Can you mentally say alright it has now sprouted?
Can you say that alright I will read this mantra to you or Bible to you or do this will
it rise?
No, it won't.
It's a living process.
You have to place it in the Mother Earth spontaneously it will rise.
You don't have to say anything, you don't have to imagine anything, it will rise.
That's what it is that this Kundalini has to be awakened in the same manner, in the
living process.
Now many people are surprised that I don't charge any money.
How can you charge money for love first of all?
And this love which is so spontaneous, I don't do anything, I'm just standing before
you, I'm doing nothing at all but if that love is flowing all over and if you get this
awakening because of my presence, I'm doing nothing.
It's your own.
Whatever is your own, this Kundalini is your own, your desire is your own and if you
achieve your realization, it's your own.
What is there to charge for to be honest, I don't do anything.
There's no obligation at all.
It's just a catalyst.
Then you become the catalyst, then the third person becomes the catalyst, everybody can
become the catalyst but one has to be honest and truthful.
Otherwise you cannot find truth.
If you are living with myths, how can you find the truth?
Now the modern Sahaja Yoga, what I call it, whatever the way I'm trying, is a little
different that people could have used before.
Like they first wanted to clear chakras after chakras, everything and then go through
all kinds of penances and all that and rise the Kundalini because people needed this
cleansing.
Now what I thought was the easiest method is somehow or other to raise the Kundalini,
somehow make it even a little glimpse of the light into people, let the light coming in
the lamp, let the lamp be seen by the people themselves.
When the Kundalini rises, you see, there's flickering say of the light, you can see yourself
what's wrong with you, which chakras catching, where is the problem and then it's very easy
to correct.