So everything, the timing, everything has to be worked out according to the need of the
spirit and not need of the growth.
When that happens, you hold slowly and understandingly the whole pattern of the Divine, how it
works out.
And that is how you understand the dynamism of time.
Because you live in the present, not in the future or in the past.
Actually, the past doesn't exist and the future has not come.
We don't know what future is.
To come in the present, you have to be the spirit.
When you are in the spirit, then you realize that this present is the reality, the rest
is a myth.
When the Kundalini rises, she passes attention into an area or she penetrates into an area
where there is silence.
Because it thought rises and falls on.
Another thought rises and falls on.
In between these two thoughts, this area exists of the present.
Now, but if I say, you stop at this point, to be at this point, you can.
Your mind is jumping either on the past or on the future.
But the Kundalini is the only thing that stops at present moment, so that you don't consider
the past and the future.
But you enjoy the present, the complete dynamism of the present and you are effective.
You are dynamic.
You can do thousand one thing, which normally you cannot do.
And you are surprised how it works out.
The divine has its own plans, has its own understanding.
And we cannot make the divine to work as we want.
We have to accept whatever the divine does and manages and then we see the miracles of
the divine and we are surprised how efficient it is, how beautiful it is.
Like a machine, we feel the efficiency of the divine.
But above all, we feel the compassion, the love, the understanding of the divine.
But first we must rise up to that.
And for that one has to grow in the awareness of the Spirit.
If we cannot develop the awareness of the Spirit, we lose that magnitude, which we have
to achieve.
So what is to be respected is the Spirit after realization, because it gives you the truth.
To understand the truth, you have to be the Spirit.
Otherwise whatever you understand is false.
It's not true.
Because of your mental projection, you think that that is the truth is not true.
For example, now, if I am sitting on this chair, you would know any time that I ever sat
on this chair.
But supposing there is a realized soul who comes round, immediately, he will know that
there was someone like me.
For example, I say that Mozart was a realized soul.
How do I know?
He's dead now.
Because we can feel it from vibration that he was a realized soul.
I say Abraham Lincoln was a realized soul.
Not because the way he lived or what he did, that was just an expression or was the symptom
of his witness.
But because when you think of him, you get cool breeze in your hand.
Tremendously cool breeze, soothe, which crawls over you.
Oh, that's Abraham Lincoln.
We do not know where we spend our time.
What people are important to us till we are desperate.
We waste our time catering to something absolutely useless.
And then suddenly we discover God, what a waste of time.
What a waste of energy, what a waste of money.
This man was a cheat.
He cheated me.
This work was all false.
Why did I waste my time there?
After realization, you become the absolute.
There is no relative value.
You do not judge anything relatively.
We just know what is absolute.
And once you know the absolute, you are a coxure about it.
There's no revering.
Thus you become an extremely powerful person and you know the truth about everything.
Now the truth is very simple that you are the spirit and you are not the body.
You are not the mind and you are not the ego or your conditioning.
But you are the free spirit, just the truth is.
But it is not just a mental truth, but is actually so and has to be actualized.
The third thing that happens to you, apart from your awareness becoming the truth, the
complete knowledge, you become the source of joy.
Not that you only receive the joy, but you become the source of joy, the source of
bliss and the source of peace.